Anger and Love
While a man was polishing his
new car, his 6 yr old son
picked up a stone and
scratched lines on the side
of the car.
In anger, the man took the
child’s hand and hit it many
times; not realizing he was
using a wrench.
At the hospital,
the child lost all his
fingers due to multiple
fractures.
When the child saw his
father…..with painful eyes he
asked, ‘Dad when will my
fingers grow back?’ The man
was so hurt and speechless;
he went back to his car and
kicked it a lot of times.
Devastated by his own
actions…….sitting in front of
that car he looked at the
scratches; the child had
written
‘LOVE YOU DAD’.
Anger and Love have no
limits; choose the latter to
have a beautiful,
lovely life…..
Things are to be used and
people are to be loved.
But the problem in today’s
world is that,
People are used and things
are loved….Let’s be careful
to keep this thought in mind:
Things are to be used,
but People are to be loved.
Watch your thoughts;
they become words.
Watch your words;
they become actions.
Watch your actions;
they become habits.
Watch your habits they become
character;Watch your
character; it becomes your
destiny.