DEBATED GLORY FOR SURE
Where to, from here?
In the world we could know
self, only after peeping in
the mirror, always with a
lurking terror,
where a mythology begins with
the question like who am I;
where are we;
perpetually questioning what
we are doing,
why are we doing,
and looking up to the sky,
a futile try,
to know from the so called
Lord, in the sky, why,
why me, why?
I have yet to find an answer,
to such lurking questions,
and many more,
with tension that keep all of
us on toes, many a time at
brink of unknown throe,
at sleepless nights,
with all our might,
like Romare Bearden asking
Odysseus, if he could answers
to our tormenting questions
from his near fatal voyages,
or begging Dharmaraj
Yudhisther if Yaksha asked
him such questions,
as we ask ourselves,
and could he answer,
not only to save his
brothers, but the entire
humankind!
The journey always rough,
some miserable god tough,
in the belly of the earth,
and in the bosom of the sea,
always looking for
retribution, people always
succumbing to pollution;
the hero is the one who comes
home, even if it’s by process
of elimination -
a playwright can make a
mythology asking - what’s
wrong with this song as a
solution? It is like Arjuna
asking Krishna about coming
home from the war, so why
are you a hero and why are
you still coming home from a
war and not only men even
women raped and die in wars,
in the name of ablution,
even if it’s not the expected
dishonor and death then what
attribution and -----
wait that’s not a question,
but it’s still a mythology,
if that’s the only anthology
we are told to live with,
for sure a failing posology,
for our debated glory for
sure.