MADE OUR HANDS TO RISE
Leisurely we strolled down from Godrej Baug
Taking a short cut from Malabar Hill path
And as we landed at the mouth of Marine Drive
A wow escaped with surprise
For the perfect queen’s necklace
And joyously we went on to the Gymkhana
Where some had their pegs
Some bhel
Some their tea
Which made us realize
That our legs had become heavy
As lead
From the unaccustomed path
We did tread
And a cab was hailed
As our strength paled
In front of
Aging zest
And as we zipped the blissful path
And as we passed
The spot
Where Kasab had pumped bullets
All over the patriot
Tukaram Ombale
The dare devil
Whose statue
Made our hands to rise
To salute
Even the silhouette
Of his statue
In the darkness
Blinking with innumerable lights!