MAKING SANE CUCKOO
Was it a coincident that the
first post I opened in my
mobile, it threatened to tell
me, about the 25 most
dangerous places on earth,
the list surprisingly
included Mumbai too,
albeit it is one of the
safest cities in India,
in comparison to many more,
as dangerous as those in
Mexico, Brazil, South Africa,
Congo etc, or was it a
conspiracy that the very next
post was from Lallanatop,
talking about Ek Kavita Roz,
a poem a day,
the one in question was sans
any title, by Darpan Shah,
that also glorified crime and
assured that all the crimes
would be rewarded in haven,
and the priests,
and the pundits and the
mullahs and sheikhs would
burn in the hell fire?
I could not decipher,
if that was true or a satire,
or a figment of the mind a
frustrated shyre,
a poet penning in Urdu,
not knowing whether to boo,
or to eschew the desire,
sans any clue,
what the hell is the poetic
brew, painting trepidation,
drowned in murky political
stew, not only spreading,
but prevailing like the
threat of ubiquitous,
CORONAVIRUS flu,
making sane cuckoo!