Ramu and the Mangoes
A rich man lived in a small
town in Tamil Nadu.
One day he brought home two
large and juicy mangoes.
He gave them to his servent
and said, “ Here Ramu,
take these to the kitchen and
cut them.
Make two cup of coffee too.
A friend of mine will be
coming soon.
Make the mangoes and coffee
when he comes,”
Ramu took the mangoes to the
kitchen and cut them with a
knife.
Then, to make sure they were
not sour, he put one piece in
his mouth.
Ah, how sweet it tasted!
If I eat just one more piece,
the master will never know,”
he thought.
He put one more piece into
his mouth, one more…
In a few minutes,
the plate was empty!
Ramu felt a little frightened.
The master was sure to beat
him.
Just then he heard his master
calling, “Ramu,
have you cut the mangoes ?
Keep the coffee ready too.
My friend will be here any
minute.”
Poor Ramu.
What was he to do now ?
He had already eaten up the
mangoes.
He thought quickly,
and got an idea.
“Oh master,”he replied.
“The knife is blunt.
I can’t cut the mangoes with
it.”
“You fool!
Why didn’t you tell me
earlier ?” the master shouted.
“Bring the knife here.
I’ll sharpen it for you.”
Ramu took a large and blunt
knife from the kitchen and
gave it to his master.
While the master was busy
sharpening it,
Ramu quietly went out of the
house.
He saw his master’s friend
coming up the road.
Ramu ran to meet him,.
“Sir, sir,” he said to the
friend, “have you had a fight
with my master ?
He says that he will cut off
both your ears !”
The friend stared in surprise.
“Fight ?” he said.
“We didn’t really have a
fight.
But yesterday when he came to
my house, I put on his
chappals by mistake.
Now why should he want to cut
off my ears for a little
thing like that?”
“I’m telling you, Sir,
he wants to cut off your
ears.” Ramu said again.
“If you don’t believe  me.
you can see for  yourself.
But mind, don’t let him catch
you!”
The friend crept up to an
open window and saw the
master of the house
sharpening a big knife.
“My goodness!” he cried.
“He really wants to cut off
my ears!
I had better run away before
he sees me.” He turned round
and ran back the way he had
come.
Ramu then ran to his master
crying, “Master, master,
your friend has taken both
the mangoes.
There he is, running away!”
The master looked up and saw
his friend running away at
top speed.
He rushed out and ran after
his friend.
“Stop!
Stop!” he shouted.
“Keep one of them if you
like, but let me have the
other one!” The friend looked
back and saw the master
running after him with a big
knife in one hand.
He screamed in terror.
Doubling his speed,
he vanished in the distance.
The master soon gave up the
chase and went back to his
house.
Calling Ramu, he said,
“I never knew how greedy this
man was, and a thief too!
Thank you for telling me.” He
then went out and came out
with two more large and juicy
mangoes.
Giving them to Ramu, he said,
“Here Ramu, you eat one.
And cut the other one for me.”