THE EPIC IN THE SAND
Before the heavenly lamp
In the east could light
The ten into eight
Became terror of fright
As if possessed by
Ma Kali herself
They made
The foes’ graves like a delf
Albeit outnumbered
Yet with glory they stood
The barrage of
3.5K from sand and wood
Fistful of them
Stood their ground
With their every
Blood curdling sound
An enemy was dropped
An enemy was caught
As steadily the invaders
On knee they brought
With valor
Few did lay their lives
Before a foe each
Was put to knives
Before the day
Traveled dia-deca* length
Nation’s warriors
Arrived in strength
And together they brought
The foe to its knees
As if a butterfly had
Trapped swarms of bees
Their guns kept spewing
Only inferno
Telling the foe
Forever to know
It had woken
Its sleeping death
Forever to throttle
Its evil breath
Outnumbered yet the brave slaughtered
Tens and tens
As if the foe was
A pen of hens
And when the sun showered
Its silver on sand
With glee foes cadavers
It just tanned!
Thus with blood
They wrote epic in sand
For their valor
To be played by every band
The anthem
They called Shaurya Divas**
With pride to be sung
With national vivas
With élan they retrieved
The Sardar Post
To their valor
Nation raises a toast!
Indebted moist eyes
With billion salutes
Look up to you Ati Veers***
All residing in the Bootes****!
Forever realms would sing
This CRPF Saga
On their cenotaphs
On their Darga!