Two and Three
In a small village in
Himachal (A state in northern
hilly region in India.) lived
an old man and his wife.
Both were over seventy and
both loved one another.
Only five other families
lived in this tiny village.
One cold winter evening the
old man and his wife were
sitting inside their hut.
Outside it was snowing.
Suddenly the old man looked
up and said, “I wish we could
have some pakodas (Salty
snacks prepared by frying
vegetable mixed in gram flour
batter).
I very much feel like eating
pakodas today.”
“I’ll see if there’s any
besan (Gram flour) in the
house,” his wife replied.
She got up and opened the tin
of besan.
“Oh, there’s only a little
bit here,” she said.
“It’s too cold to go out and
buy more.
So I shall make pakodas from
this little bit of besan.”
The old woman lighted the
fire and made pakodas.
She made five.
She gave her husband three
pakodas and herself took two.
But the old man would not
take the palcodas.
How can I eat three when you
are getting only two ?” he
said.
“Take one pakoda from me.”
“Two pakodas are enough for
me,” his wife replied.
“It is you who asked for them.
You take three now.
Tomorrow I shall get more
besan from the shop and make
pakodas.
I can then take one more than
you.”
“We’ll see about that later,”
the old man said.
“But today you must eat three
pakodas.”
They kept arguing like this
all evening.
Night fell, but they had
still not eaten the pakodas.
At last they agreed on a plan.
“It is quite late,” they said.
“So let us go to sleep now.
Tomorrow morning,
the one who gets up first
will have to eat three
pakodas.”
So they both went to sleep.
Morning came.
But still they kept lying in
bed, eyes closed.
Each wanted the other to get
up first, for each wanted the
other one to have three
pakodas.
It grew quite late and the
sun rose high in the sky.
But still they would not get
up.
The neighbours saw that their
door was still closed.
They got worried.
“What is the matter with the
old couple ?” they said.
“They still have not got up.
Let us go and find out if
they are all right.”
The neighbours went and
knocked at the door.
They called out to the old
couple, but there was no
reply from inside.
Then the neighbours hammered
at the door with their fists.
But still the door remained
closed.
Now they got really worried.
“We shall have to break the
door,” they said.
“The old people may be ill.”
So they brought an axe and
broke open the door.
They then went in and saw the
old man and his wife lying on
their cots with eyes closed.
“Oh no,” they said.
“They are both dead!
Let us take them to the
burning place.”
When the old man heard this
he shot up in alarm.
He realised that they would
both be burnt alive.
“Oh very well,” he cried.
“I shall eat three andyou can
eat the other two.” On
hearing this the old woman
also shot up and cried,
“That’s what I’ve been
telling you all this time.
If you had listened to me,
we could have eaten them last
night.
We wouldn’t have gone hungry
all night then.
But we can eat them now.”
When the neighbours heard
this they were alarmed.
They ran out of the door
shouting.
“Run!
Run for your life!
The ghosts of the old man and
his wife are after us!
They are going to eat us all
up!
The old man’s ghost will eat
up three families,
and his wife’s ghost will eat
up the other two families in
the village !”
The old man and his wife were
surprised.
They ran after the neighbours
to tell them that they were
not ghosts.
At this the neighbours were
even more frightened.
They ran faster still.
Much later the old man and
his wife told the neighbours
about the pakodas.
When they heard this,
they burst out laughing.
That day the old woman
brought more besan from the
shop and made lots of pakodas.
Then she invited everyone in
the village for a feast of
pakodas.
You see, she was sorry that
she and her old man had given
everyone such a fright.
Third Story for You
Hospital Window
Two men, both seriously ill,
occupied the same hospital
room.
One man was allowed to sit up
in his bed for an hour each
afternoon to help drain the
fluid from his lungs.
His bed was next to the
room’s only window.
The other man had to spend
all his time flat on his back.
The men talked for hours on
end.
They spoke of their wives and
families, their homes,
their jobs, their involvement
in the military service,
where they had been on
vacation.
Every afternoon,
when the man in the bed by
the window could sit up,
he would pass the time by
describing to his roommate
all the things he could see
outside the window.
The man in the other bed
began to live for those one
hour periods where his world
would be broadened and
enlivened by all the activity
and color of the world
outside.
The window overlooked a park
with a lovely lake.
Ducks and swans played on the
water while children sailed
their model boats.
Young lovers walked arm in
arm amidst flowers of every
color and a fine view of the
city skyline could be seen in
the distance.
As the man by the window
described all this in
exquisite details,
the man on the other side of
the room would close his eyes
and imagine this picturesque
scene.
One warm afternoon,
the man by the window
described a parade passing by.
Although the other man could
not hear the band,
he could see it in his mind’s
eye as the gentleman by the
window portrayed it with
descriptive words.
Days, weeks and months passed.
One morning, the day nurse
arrived to bring water for
their baths only to find the
lifeless body of the man by
the window, who had died
peacefully in his sleep.
She was saddened and called
the hospital attendants to
take the body away.
As soon as it seemed
appropriate, the other man
asked if he could be moved
next to the window.
The nurse was happy to make
the switch, and after making
sure he was comfortable,
she left him alone.
Slowly, painfully,
he propped himself up on one
elbow to take his first look
at the real world outside.
He strained to slowly turn to
look out the window beside
the bed.
It faced a blank wall.
The man asked the nurse what
could have compelled his
deceased roommate who had
described such wonderful
things outside this window.
The nurse responded that the
man was blind and could not
even see the wall.
She said, ‘Perhaps he just
wanted to encourage you.’
Epilogue:
There is tremendous happiness
in making others happy,
despite our own situations.
Shared grief is half the
sorrow, but happiness when
shared, is doubled.
If you want to feel rich,
just count all the things you
have that money can’t buy.
‘Today is a gift,
that is why it is called
The Present.’